Zhiming Hu

Curriculum Vitae

Perceptual User Interfaces Group
Biomechanics & Biorobotics Group
University of Stuttgart, Germany

(**)* (+86) 131-6739-7064

□ cranehzm@gmail.com

'□ cranehzm.github.io

Ph.D.

Research Interests

My research interests include virtual reality, visual attention, human-computer interaction, eye tracking, and human intention prediction. During my Ph.D. career, I focused on analysis, prediction, and recognition of human visual attention in virtual reality. I am now extending my research to human intention prediction, especially human arm movement prediction.

Academic Positions

Post-doctoral Researcher

2022.08-now

2013.09-2017.07

Perceptual User Interfaces Group, University of Stuttgart, Led by Prof. Andreas Bulling Biomechanics & Biorobotics Group, University of Stuttgart, Led by Prof. Syn Schmitt

Education

Ph.D. in Computer Software and Theory
 Graphics & Interactive Lab., Peking University, Supervised by Prof. Guoping Wang

• **B.Eng.** in Optical Engineering School of Optics and Photonics, **Beijing Institute of Technology**

Teaching Activities

Invited Speaker

- Human-Computer Interaction, Peking University, 2021
- Orientation Course for Freshmen: University, Youth, and Life, Beijing Institute of Technology, 2017

Teaching Assistant

- Computer Graphics, Peking University, 2018
- Image and Video-Based 3D Reconstruction, Peking University, 2018
- Programming Basics, Peking University, 2018

Professional Activities

Reviewing

- o 2022: CVPR, IEEE VR, IJHCI, ECCV, ISMAR
- o 2021: IMWUT, TVCG, ICCV, IEEE VR, ISMAR
- 2020: TVCG, IEEE VR, ISMAR

Organizing Committee

• Technical program committee member for I-SCMT 2022

Invited Talks

- o Southeast University, China, Hosted by Prof. Ding Ding, June, 2022
- o IEEE VR 2022, Hosted by Prof. Kiyoshi Kiyokawa, March, 2022
- o GAMES Webinar 2021, Hosted by Prof. Xubo Yang, September, 2021
- 2019 International Conference on VR/AR and 3D Display, Hosted by Prof. Feng Xu, June 2019

Awards & Honors

- Outstanding Graduates Prize in Peking University, 2022
- National Scholarship, 2021
- TVCG Best Journal Nominees Award (IEEE VR 2021), 2021
- o CSC (China Scholarship Council) Scholarship, 2020
- Second-Class Scholarship of Peking University, 2020
- Chancellor's Scholarship, 2020
- Leo KoGuan Scholarship, 2019
- Leader Scholarship, 2017
- Outstanding Graduates Prize in Beijing Institute of Technology, 2017
- National Scholarship, 2016
- Honorable Mention of Mathematical Contest in Modeling, 2016
- National Encouragement Scholarship, 2015
- Third Prize of the National College Students Composition Competition, 2015
- Third Prize of Beijing Humanistic Knowledge Competition, 2014
- National Scholarship, 2014

— Publications

Journal Articles:

- Zehui Lin, Xiang Gu, Sheng Li, <u>Zhiming Hu</u>, Guoping Wang. Intentional Head-Motion Assisted Locomotion for Reducing Cybersickness. IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics, 2022.
- 2. **Zhiming Hu**, Andreas Bulling, Sheng Li, Guoping Wang. EHTask: Recognizing User

- Tasks from Eye and Head Movements in Immersive Virtual Reality. IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics, 2022.
- 3. **Zhiming Hu**, Sheng Li, Meng Gai. Research progress of user task prediction and algorithm analysis (in Chinese). Journal of Graphics, 2021, 42(3): 367-375.
- 4. **Zhiming Hu**, Andreas Bulling, Sheng Li, Guoping Wang. FixationNet: Forecasting Eye Fixations in Task-Oriented Virtual Environments. IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics, 2021, 27(5): 2681-2690.

TVCG Best Journal Nominees Award

- 5. **Zhiming Hu**, Sheng Li, Congyi Zhang, Kangrui Yi, Guoping Wang, Dinesh Manocha. DGaze: CNN-Based Gaze Prediction in Dynamic Scenes. IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics, 2020, 26(5): 1902-1911.
- 6. **Zhiming Hu**, Sheng Li, Meng Gai. Temporal continuity of visual attention for future gaze prediction in immersive virtual reality. Virtual Reality & Intelligent Hardware, 2020, 2(2): 142-152.
- 7. **Zhiming Hu**, Congyi Zhang, Sheng Li, Guoping Wang, Dinesh Manocha. SGaze: A Data-Driven Eye-Head Coordination Model for Realtime Gaze Prediction. IEEE Transactions on Visualization and Computer Graphics, 2019, 25(5): 2002-2010.

Conference Papers:

- Zhiming Hu. Eye Fixation Forecasting in Task-Oriented Virtual Reality. Proceedings of the 2021 IEEE Conference on Virtual Reality and 3D User Interfaces Abstracts and Workshops, 2021: 707-708.
- 2. Zhiming Hu. Gaze Analysis and Prediction in Virtual Reality. Proceedings of the 2020 IEEE Conference on Virtual Reality and 3D User Interfaces Abstracts and Workshops, 2020: 543-544.